I am a computer scientist specialized in the area of program analysis and verification, distributed systems, and cyber-physical systems. Program verification is the part of software engineering dedicated to showing that a piece of software has no bugs. In my academic research, I worked on improving software by developing theoretical models to better understand software artifacts and algorithms to analyze them.

| | Transportation Experience |
|-----------------|---|
| 2022.10 | Quality assurance lead , <i>Signaloid</i> , Cambridge, UK Remote work from Switzerland |
| 2022.01–2022.09 | Consultant, Signaloid, Cambridge, UK Remote work from Switzerland |
| 2016.12–2021.11 | Research group leader , <i>Max Planck Institute for Software Systems</i> , Kaiserslautern, Germany |
| 2013.10-2016.9 | Postdoctoral researcher, MIT CSAIL, Cambridge, USA |

Education

Professional Experience

In Martin C. Rinard's group.

| 09.2009–09.2013 | PhD , <i>Institute of Science and Technology Austria</i> , Klosterneuburg, Austria Under supervision of Thomas A. Henzinger |
|-----------------|--|
| 09.2007-07.2009 | Master , École Polytechnique Fédérale, Lausanne, Switzerland Master in Computer Science with specialisation in Foundations of Software |
| 09.2004–07.2007 | Bachelor , École Polytechnique Fédérale, Lausanne, Switzerland Bachelor in Computer Science |
| 08.1999–06.2004 | Maturité gymnasiale , <i>Lycée Collège des Creusets</i> , Sion, Switzerland High School in math section (specialisation: physics and numerical methods) |

Interships

| 07.2012–08.2012 | Intern , <i>Max Planck Institute for Software Systems</i> , Saarbrücken, Germany One month internship under supervision of Ruzica Piskac. |
|-----------------|---|
| 05.2012-06.2012 | Research consultant , <i>Microsoft Research</i> , Redmond, USA Three weeks consulting mandate to work with Shaz Qadeer and Ethan Jackson. |
| 11.2011-03.2012 | Research intern , <i>Microsoft Research</i> , Redmond, USA Three months internship with Shaz Qadeer. |
| 07.2007–09.2007 | Intern , Simon Fraser University, Vancouver, Canada Two months internship at the Software Reliability Lab with Dirk Beyer. |
| 2006–2008 | Research assistant , École Polytechnique Fédérale, Lausanne, Switzerland Part-time research assistant at Model and Theory of Computation laboratory. |

```
Champ-Clos 7 – 1772 Grolley, Switzerland

☐ +41 78 812 2831
• ☑ damien.zufferey@alumni.epfl.ch

⑤ dzufferey.github.io/
• ⑥ dzufferey
• ⑨ DM1nCKsAAAAJ

in damien-zufferey
```

Skills

- Leadership
 - Managing a research group with 3 PhD students
 - Organizing conference and workshops with up to 50 participants
- Programming
 - Github profile: https://github.com/dzufferey
 - Programming language:
 - \cdot experienced in C/C++ and Scala
 - · competent in Java, Python, Typescript, and shell scripting
- Languages
 - French (native)
 - English (proficient)
 - German (upper-intermediate)

Academic and Teaching Experience

Here are a summary of my academic career in numbers. (Details in my long for academic CV.)

- I published 37 peer-reviewed scientific papers.
- My results have been cited more than 1200 times and my h-index is 18.
- I organized 3 international conference and workshops.
- O I have been in 20 program committee and reviewed for 26 conferences and journals.
- I have supervised 3 PhD students and 3 master thesis.
- O I co-taught 7 classes in computer science at the master level (TU Kaiserslautern).

References

Available upon request

Awards

- Excellency Scholarships at the Master level from EPFL.
- Graduated best in class from my Bachelor at EPFL.
- Silver Medal of the ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (Regionals, South-Western Europe) in 2007 with EPFL (6th place, Swiss champions, team with Frédéric Dubut and Christian Kauth)
- Bronze Medal of the ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (Regionals, South-Western Europe) in 2006 with EPFL (9th place, Swiss champions, team with Frédéric Dubut and Abhishek Garg)